# Ho Duong, MSc

## Sr. Software Engineer at Cosatech

ho\_duong2003@yahoo.com

## Summary

More than 8 years working as senior software engineer. I have chances working on very large projects and many OS platform (Windows, Linux, Mac) most of time is Windows, and some open source library as xpdf, cximage. Most of my projects requite high performance and low memory and cpu usage so that C/C++ language is a best choice. Other I have experience about : XML, xPath, XSLT, C#, Delphi, Win32, MFC, STL, COM, RMI, Service, Web Service. some DBMS : SQL Lite, My SQL, MS SQL, Firebird. Specialties: C/C++

## Experience

## Open for new opportunities, especially Sr. C++ engineer! Thanks at Cosatech

May 2013 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Working on Core of CIS system for a TOP 500 fortune Company major in Gas and Oils located in Chicago. Handle a team to investigation root cause of Defects and Fix-It. Using VS C++, .net (VB.net,C#.net), vbscript, MS SQL on Windows System.

## Senior Software Engineer at OPSWAT

March 2013 - May 2013 (3 months)

Have a short chance working on fixing Defects and support New Features of a SDK for security softwares. Using C++ on Windows, Mac and Linux.

## Senior Software Engineer at Content Interface Corporation

May 2009 - April 2013 (4 years)

R&D Custom Automation Tools - Language : C/C++, Win32, MFC, XML - OS: Windows

## **Software Engineer at Content Interface Corporation**

May 2007 - May 2009 (2 years 1 month)

Member of Editor, Core and DSS team - Language : C/C++, Win32, MFC, COM, Carbon, Cocoa - OS: Windows, Windows Mobile, Mac OS, Linux.

## Software Engineer at Saigon Software Park

October 2005 - April 2007 (1 year 7 months)

- Languages: Delphi, Firebird - OS: Windows

## Projects

## **Watermarking System**

January 2004 to January 2005

Members:Ho Duong, MSc

This is my graduate thesis. In this project I'm using a digital watermarking algorithms to embed text signal into a image, sound or video file.

## **Human Resource Management**

November 2005 to April 2007

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+Language : Delphi +BDMS : FireBird +Roles : Feature implementation (2 big features : social insurance, payroll), customization software(depending on customer request), supporter, fixing bugs.

## Porting Codec Library for Image Processing Base on Windows to Mac OS

August 2007 to February 2008

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

-Overview: CIC have a Image Codec (base on opensource lib CxImage) already build on Windows using VC7, my task is porting this codec to cocoa, xcode. -Language: porting from VC7 to cocoa, xcode -Roles: main developer

#### **Customize software**

February 2008 to March 2008

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+about project: this is cross platform tools, can build on both Windows and Linux. This tool add limited features for CIC app. +Languages: C++ console (VC7), C++ console(KDE) +Roles: main developer for this project.

### Research on PDF rendering engine

March 2008 to February 2009

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

-About Project: current CIC using Adobe Acrobat SDK as PDF rendering engine. but this SDK requite end user must install Adobe Acrobat Professional and just working on windows OS. My task is investigate new engine can working on both windows and linux. My result is a open source lib xpdf, it working very well for our product. Language: C/C++, VC7. -Roles: Researcher and write Demo app.

#### **DSS (Digital Signature System) software**

January 2009 to April 2009

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

-About Product : Management Resources and Scheduling what resource will display on monitor of kiosk. - Languages : VC7 console, XML. -Main Developer, Fixing Bugs.

#### Watchdog software

April 2009 to April 2009

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

-About Product : Watching a App is Hung or Crash and then restart them-self. -Language : VC7 -Roles : Main developer

## Search and detect location of String on PDF Page(s)

## April 2009 to June 2009

## Members: Ho Duong, MSc

-About Project: a Request for a searching text on a ePaper website publishing from a soft copy as PDF format of a paper, they request a software can extract all text on PDF page included location of this text. - Languages: VC7 -Roles: Main researcher and developer.

#### FTPUploader software

April 2009 to June 2009

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

-About : a software starting on daily timer to processing and then publishing to a FTP server. -Language : VC7 -Roles : main developer.

#### **SceneCreator**

July 2009 to March 2012

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+ Language : MFC,VC7, Windows Form, xslt, XML Dom, xpath + Database : XML + Roles : Analysis, template design, main researcher and developer, Fixing Bugs.

## **Cywee Project**

October 2009 to October 2010

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+About Project : Outsourcing for Cywee Company. +Language : VC7, VC10. +DBMS : SQL Lite, XML.

+Roles: Build automation tools to management media resources.

## Nintendo Project

June 2010 to February 2011

Members:Ho Duong, MSc

+ Language : VC7, console, xslt, XML Dom, xpath + Database : XML + Roles : Research&Develop, Fixing Bugs

#### eDir

February 2011 to November 2011

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+Brief Overview: eDir is a complete solution to replace the traditional directories in office building with an electronic one. It employs enVision as the display engine on top of a touch screen. A building directory is a collection of name plates of tenants in the building. It tells a visitor the room number and floor of a company. eDir aims to improve the visitor experience (compared to the traditional directory) and to provide more information than just names, rooms and floors. +Language: MFC, VC7, Windows Form +Database: xls +Roles: Research & Develop, Fixing Bugs

#### **ABC**

June 2011 to June 2012

Members:Ho Duong, MSc

+ Language : MFC, VC10, Windows Form + Database : XML + Roles : Analysis, main developer, Fixing Bugs.

#### **EDF**

April 2011 to November 2011

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+ brief overview : a system to convert PDF, jpg, bmp documents for interactive viewing on a touch screen. + Language : C++/VC7, console + Roles : RnD, Fixing Bugs.

#### **iZoomCreator**

April 2012 to September 2012

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+ brief overview : a system convert image, video to mosaic format. + Language : MFC, VC10, Windows Form + Roles : RnD, Fixing Bugs.

## SkyWall

June 2012 to June 2012

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

#### InterlliWall

August 2012 to Present

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

+ Brief overview: Sharp has asked CIC to develop a software system for its IntelliWall display. IntelliWall is a 9x3 array of screens. + Language: VC7, Windows Form + Roles: automate the conversion from raw content (videos, images, PPT, PDF and Exl..etc). Depending on the input content, the system will auto convert them to enVision applications, with as little user input as possible.

## **1Second Capture**

January 2015 to Present

Members: Ho Duong, MSc

I wrote this app with intent to keep 1Second movie everyday of my first daughter! And sharing for everyone have the same purpose! https://plus.google.com/116538760669391366640/videos

## Skills & Expertise

Visual C++ (Advanced, 6 years experience)

MFC (Advanced, 4 years experience)

Win32 (Advanced, 4 years experience)

C++

Microsoft SQL Server

Windows

Win32 API

.NET

**Software Development** 

OOP

**MySQL** 

**XML** 

**ASP.NET** 

**Web Services** 

## Education

## **University of Science HCMC**

Master, Computer Science, 2010 - 2012

Activities and Societies: when learning MSc I have a change to research about Principle of Programming Language, Advanced DBMS, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Voice Recognition, Image Processing. I am not expert about this fields but I know "how it working" and help I have more knowledge about big world of Computer Science.

## **FPT Aptech**

Diploma, ACCP 2005, 2006 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Receive a Scholarship for excellent students

## **Hung Vuong University**

BS, Information System, 2001 - 2005

Activities and Societies: Receive a Scholarship of Tri Tue Viet Nam 2005 Exam (Full Scholarship at Aptech for a course 2 year).

## Honors and Awards

Join a TV Game Show (February 2007) Happy Birthday

### Interests

swimming, table tennis....

# Ho Duong, MSc

Sr. Software Engineer at Cosatech

ho\_duong2003@yahoo.com



Contact Ho on LinkedIn